Food is a animation, comedy film directed by Jan Švankmajer.
Examines the human relationship with food by
showing breakfast, lunch, and dinner.
1st Guest, played by Ludvík Šváb.
2nd Guest, played by Josef Fiala.
3rd Guest, played by Bedřich Glaser.
Elegant Guest, played by Jan Kraus.
Desolate Guest, played by Pavel Marek.
Waiter, played by Jaromír Kallista.
Soul Food is a 1997 American comedy-drama film
written and directed by George Tillman Jr.
in his major studio debut.
Featuring an ensemble cast, the film stars Vanessa Williams, Vivica A.
Fox, Nia Long, Michael Beach, Mekhi Phifer, Jeffrey D.
Sams, Irma P.
Hall, Gina Ravera and Brandon Hammond.
The story centers on the trials of an extended Black American family, held together by
longstanding family traditions which begin to fade as serious problems take center stage.
Tillman based the family in the film on his own and Soul Food was widely acclaimed for presenting a
more positive image of African-Americans than is typically seen in Hollywood films.
In 2000, Showtime premiered a one-hour television series based upon the film.
In 2015, it was announced that 20th Century Fox is planning a sequel
for the film called More Soul Food, written by Tillman.
The tone is lighthearted.